<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Fnord]]></title>
  <link href="http://fnord.phfactor.net/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://fnord.phfactor.net/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-02T16:16:21-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://fnord.phfactor.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[pfh@phfactor.net]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://www.statiked.com/">Statiked</generator>

  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Image links]]></title>
    <link href="http://fnord.phfactor.net/2014/08/01/Image-links.html"/>
    <updated>2014-08-02T23:33:59+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fnord.phfactor.net/2014/08/01/Image-links.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You think it'd be easy: Post an image that links somewhere. It's <a href="http://meta.stackexchange.com/questions/2133/whats-the-recommended-syntax-for-an-image-with-a-link">not.</a></p>
<p>Not sure where the bug is. Pardon me while I poke and experiment here:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.phfactor.net">![Orient watch](http://www.phfactor.net/pics/watches/orient.jpg)</a></p>
<p>Which works on <a href="http://www.markdownviewer.com">markdown viewer</a>. Talked to Statiked support and it 
is a library problem, they use <a href="https://github.com/mdiep/MMMarkdown">MMMarkdown</a> and it doesn't support
nested syntax. Yet.</p>
<p>So I have to use inline HTML. Let's try that:</p>
<p><a href="http://fnord.phfactor.net"><img src="http://www.phfactor.net/pics/watches/orient.jpg"></a></p>
<p>OK, we have a workaround!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
<entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to Fnord, Statiked version]]></title>
    <link href="http://fnord.phfactor.net/2014/07/30/Welcome-to-Fnord-Statiked-version.html"/>
    <updated>2014-08-01T15:55:50+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fnord.phfactor.net/2014/07/30/Welcome-to-Fnord-Statiked-version.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The blog platform and server are now both changed - I've been using Octopress and self-hosting, but the
Rake-based workflow was painful and slow, and while I don't regret funding the Ghost project they still haven't had
time to add file import, so here's Plan B for now:</p>
<ul>
<li>Switch to <a href="http://statiked.com">Statiked</a> as an editor</li>
<li>Switch to GitHub Pages for hosting. Why? Because it's supported by Statiked. ;)</li>
</ul>
<p>Just had a nice debug call with the author of <a href="http://statiked.com">Statiked</a>... gotta love indie developers! We did a screenshare
and debugged the problem I was having. Turns out that the GitHub API he uses can't handle the two-factor
authentication I had enabled. Disable it and voila.</p>
<p>So here we go. Pages now <a href="https://github.com/phubbard/phubbard.github.io">hosted on github</a>, and I'll see if I can import the old writing from Octopress.</p>
<p>Notes so far:</p>
<ul>
<li>Statiked doesn't parse the timestamps unless you have the '-0700' timezone offset. Odd.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
  </entry>
<entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paul tries pocketwatches]]></title>
    <link href="http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/12/23/Paul-tries-pocketwatches.html"/>
    <updated>2014-08-02T23:34:01+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/12/23/Paul-tries-pocketwatches.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday, after an epic shipping adventure involving ebay, paypal, UPS and several phone calls, my new toy arrived:</p>
<p><a href="http://stores.ebay.com/WFN-ENTERPRISES-INC"><img src="http://www.phfactor.net/pics/watches/helbros.jpg" alt="Helbros pocketwatch"></a></p>
<p>(Link to is the ebay seller who sold it to me.)</p>
<p>Bad news first - it's not really a moonphase. And it doesn't have a seconds hand. That's a hairspring window, not a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tourbillon">tourbillon.</a></p>
<p>Then again, it <em>was</em> $40USD. So I'm inclined to cut it some slack. I had wanted to check out pocket watches, but since I am pretty sure that it'll be a passing fad, I didn't want to spend much money on one. You can easily find vintage Elgin and Hamiltons on ebay, but I decided to get one new so that it wouldn't require immediate maintenance. (Finding someone to work on a mechanical clock is not easy!) As with <a href="http://www.phfactor.net/wp/?p=12">my skeletonized watch</a>, cheap and Chinese is the answer.</p>
<h3>Pros and cons</h3>
<p>The hairspring and balance wheel are visible, and you can see most of the <a href="http://www.phfactor.net/wp/?p=27">pallet fork</a> oscillating as well. It's quite fun to watch, pun intended. The two subdials are both 24hr indicators, of different sorts. The one on the left just has all 24 hours printed on it, with a simple hand pointer. The one on the right rotates at the same speed, but is printed with a day/night sort of thing. It looks like a moonphase until you look closely; this is the sort of corner-cutting you expect from cheep-and-cheerful gear. A moonphase (28-day cycle) is more complicated; if you have that the watch usually has day/date as well.</p>
<p>As with the skeletonized wristwatch, the display is busy and not instantly readable. Not bad, just not the instant read of <a href="http://www.phfactor.net/wp/?p=7">a dive-style watch.</a></p>
<p>It comes with a pocket chain, pocketknife and integrate desk stand. It's kinda cool to stand it up on your desk and watch the works of the balance.</p>
<p>The works are pretty quiet; you have to hold it up to your ear to hear the tick-tock. It looks like 5 or 6 beats per second. 17 jewels, no printing on the back, side winder stem, not waterproof.</p>
<p>Accuracy is hard to measure without a second hand; I've had it a couple of days and the error is not yet visible.</p>
<p>Helbros is an old brand; I'm guessing that (along with others) it was bought by a Chinese company to give them instant credibility.</p>
<h3>so?</h3>
<p>A perfectly reasonable, and very affordable, pocketwatch. Pocketwatches are, of course, an absurd affectation in this day and age. If you get one, it's probably just for enjoyment and odd occasions. I kind of like how it changes your sense of time - when you have to remove the watch from your pocket to look, it's a bit different than just glancing at your wrist. </p>
<p>Cool.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
<entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Putin wears Philippe, Bush wears timex]]></title>
    <link href="http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/12/21/Putin-wears-Philippe-Bush-wears-timex.html"/>
    <updated>2014-07-31T18:51:28+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/12/21/Putin-wears-Philippe-Bush-wears-timex.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So George Bush wears a $50 Timex, and Berlosconi wears a half-million-dollar Vacheron.</p>
<p><a href="http://english.pravda.ru/main/18/90/361/14979_watch.html">Pravda dishes the dirt</a> on world leaders and watches.</p>
<p>Amusing to note that Putin's watch costs one year of his official salary.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
<entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Value of Time]]></title>
    <link href="http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/12/16/The-Value-of-Time.html"/>
    <updated>2014-07-31T18:51:38+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/12/16/The-Value-of-Time.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>The origins of watch collecting are rooted in the utilitarian. When the social time coordination instrument was the village clock, social units tended to cluster around the village square. With the rise of portable, reliable watches, the individual was freed to roam independently from the center of town, and yet remain in sync with the rest of humanity. Today, with the ready availability of completely automated, mass-produced electronic watches, the raison d’etre of a fine mechanical timepiece no longer lies primarily in its timekeeping function. Today, the keystones to value in high mechanical timepieces are set in the perceived values of craft, the reconciliation of tradition and innovation, and their much more fascinating roles as a form of kinetic art and signatures of personal style.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>An <a href="http://www.worth.com/Editorial/Money-Meaning/Passion-Investments/Watches-Jewelry/Watches-The-Value-of-Time-Print.asp">interesting editorial on Worth.com</a> about watches. More oriented towards collectors and such, but has some interesting bits.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
<entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Client mode on Linksys WRT54GS]]></title>
    <link href="http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/12/11/Client-mode-on-Linksys-WRT54GS.html"/>
    <updated>2014-08-02T23:32:54+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/12/11/Client-mode-on-Linksys-WRT54GS.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have a <a href="http://slimdevices.com/">Squeezebox v1</a></p>
<p><img src="http://www.phfactor.net/wp-pics/slim_devices_squeezebox.png" alt="squeezebox" /></p>
<p>for some months now, setup to play music streamed from my Mac mini. It (the squeezebox) has been flaky ever since I got it, where it'd simply lose the connection after a while and have to be power-cycled to recover.</p>
<p>Somewhere between annoying and unusable, actually.</p>
<p>So today, based on an idea, I took a WRT54GS, <a href="http://tonesnotes.org/2005/05/01/configuring-linksys-wrt54g-wireless">set it as a client to my main wireless router</a>, and plugged the squeezebox into the linksys.</p>
<p>End result: Using the wired connection on the squeezebox seems more reliable than the wireless side. Odd, that.</p>
<p>Still messing with other variables, such as whether or not I leave itunes running. Now that I have podcasts to fetch, that's more of a necessity. However, it seems like the re-scans of the itunes library may cause playback glitches.</p>
<p>UPDATE Dec 16/05 - yep, using the bridge seems to fix the flakiness. Looks like the wireless part is just flaky.</p>
<p>UPDATE 5/07: Changing base stations to an Apple Airport Express also fixed the problem. I had to return the Linksys anyway, as it was a loaner. Stable now for several months.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
<entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free google local client.]]></title>
    <link href="http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/12/08/Free-google-local-client.html"/>
    <updated>2014-07-31T17:27:14+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/12/08/Free-google-local-client.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.bblocal.com/">bbLocal</a> is a full client for Google Local.</p>
<p>Seems good. OTA at mobile.bblocal.com. Trying it now!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
<entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is it with men and their watches?]]></title>
    <link href="http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/12/06/What-is-it-with-men-and-their-watches.html"/>
    <updated>2014-07-31T17:28:15+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/12/06/What-is-it-with-men-and-their-watches.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/g2/story/0,,1654848,00.html">...is the title of this Guardian article</a>. Not many conclusions, but worth a read. I agree with the author that our <a href="http://www.phfactor.net/wp/?p=7">relationship with our watches</a> has gotten more complicated.</p>
<p>S/he also hits the 'watches as jewelry' point that I mentioned.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
<entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Watches for flying]]></title>
    <link href="http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/12/03/Watches-for-flying.html"/>
    <updated>2014-08-02T23:32:35+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/12/03/Watches-for-flying.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm close to finishing my quest for a private pilot's license, and am still looking for a good watch to wear.</p>
<p>From personal preference, I want to have</p>
<pre><code></code></pre>
<ol>
<li><p>GMT/UTC time for weather and such</p>
</li>
<li><p>Timers, preferably two or more</p>
</li>
<li><p>Countdown timers, for things like fuel changes</p>
</li>
<li><p>Readability, under widely varying light and also with polarized sunglasses</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>As noted in my dive watch review, the Seiko fulfills #3, but that's about it. <a href="http://www.phfactor.net/wp/?p=32">The Orient and Omega</a> both do the job, or close to it. There's also the approach of <a href="http://www.phfactor.net/wp/?p=8">a dive watch with a GMT hand</a>, which provides 1,3 and part of 2.</p>
<p>However, you have to keep in mind that a fancy watch is really unnecesary. As with <a href="http://www.phfactor.net/wp/?p=7">dive watches</a>, the <em>need</em> for an elaborate flight watch with E6B slide rule and many dials is long gone. Flight watches now serve as affectations, wish fulfillment, jewelry or (rarely) functionality.</p>
<p>From Salon's <a href="http://archive.salon.com/tech/col/smith/2002/10/11/askthepilot14/index1.html">"Ask the Pilot"</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What is the purpose of the complicated watches I always see pilots wearing?</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Their purpose is this: to tell them what time it is. Many pilots feel these gaudy little devices are an essential part of their uniform, perhaps a tribute to the days when goggled aviators used their watches to … I don't know. For a number of years I owned a Mickey Mouse watch as a kind of quietly irreverent protest to this practice (it also was the only kind I could afford). My red-bezeled Swiss Army watch also does the job wonderfully. Watches are required as backups to the ship's clocks, but nothing more elaborate than a sweep hand is needed.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>(Of course, he's flying an airliner with more compute power and instruments than I'll ever have. My last Archer had the 'classic six' plus GPS and a stick-on stopwatch.)</p>
<p>Or, as <a href="http://philip.greenspun.com/flying/shopping">Philip Greenspun puts it</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Q: What do you get when you cross an ape with a pilot?
A: An ape with a big watch.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>He goes on to advocate simple and readable, which I agree with. Taken to an extreme, you can get watches from <a href="http://www.bellross.com/bellross.php">Bell &amp; Ross</a> which are styled to look like flight instruments:</p>
<p><img src="http://www.phfactor.net/pics/watches/bell-ross.jpg" alt="B&amp;R" /></p>
<p>Nice. A pity they cost thousands of dollars, though. And don't have GMT. Or timers. Or alarms. Just the looks, ma'am.</p>
<p>I also flew with a Timex for a while:</p>
<p><img src="http://www.phfactor.net/pics/watches/b17.jpg" alt="timex" /></p>
<p>(<a href="http://www.sportys.com/acb/showdetl.cfm?DID=19&amp;Product_ID=6505&amp;CATID=173">This one</a>)
 You can also get different WW2 plane logos instead of the B17 - <a href="http://www.sportys.com/acb/showprod.cfm?&amp;DID=19&amp;CATID=173&amp;ObjectGroup_ID=1253">see this page of listings</a>.</p>
<p>This is actually an OEM Timex Expedition, for $65. It's readable as heck, has a backlight for both analog and digital, and can keep track of two timezones. (E.g., GMT). The curve of the digital impairs legibility a bit, but it's pretty damn good.</p>
<p>These days, the only need for a <em>complicated</em> watch is if you lose instruments, have an ancient plane (e.g. Piper Cub) or demand to Look Like a Pilot. Once again, watches are jewelry. Pick one that's readable, functional and cheap. If you're flying, you need the money for airtime anyway.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
<entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Breitling and analog-digital]]></title>
    <link href="http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/12/03/Breitling-and-analog-digital.html"/>
    <updated>2014-08-02T23:32:20+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/12/03/Breitling-and-analog-digital.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For a long time I've lusted after a Breitling B-1 watch:</p>
<p><img src="http://www.phfactor.net/pics/watches/b1.jpg" alt="B1" /></p>
<p>A <a href="http://forums.timezone.com/index.php?t=tree&amp;goto=2234&amp;rid=0">TimeZone review is here.</a> It's a nice analog-digital combo, but vastly overpriced at 3,000USD or so. Hard to justify unless 'readable with night vision goggles' is a must-have for you.So that's right out. That's just waaaay too much money for an (admittedly nice) quartz watch. Here are some of the alternatives I've found so far:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.timex.com/bin/detail.tmx?item=048148563810"><img src="http://www.phfactor.net/pics/watches/image.tmx.jpg" alt="timex"></a></p>
<p>This is a Timex, which I've seen in person - reasonably nice, super cheap ($70 list!) and you can turn off the digital for a cleaner appearance. Timex has never had the austere simplicity of a Seiko, but it ain't bad and the price is right. Then there's the Orient CVZ00002J: </p>
<p><a href="http://www.network54.com/Forum/78440/thread/1133550200/Sold+the+black+Orient+ana-digi+a+while+back.+Missed+it%2C+so+I+bought+the+aqua+blue.+PIC"><img src="http://www.phfactor.net/pics/watches/orient.jpg" alt="Orient"></a></p>
<p>Much better. More readable face, good luminosity, better hands, very readable. 100 to 150USD. (<a href="http://www.roachman.com/orient/quartz/CVZ00001.html">Roachman has it for sale.</a>; you can also find it for about 100 on ebay) Does not have a backlight for the digital portion, alas. (See the comments for Hari's nice take on this as well!) Note that, on ebay, one seller lists this as model 'CVZ00002J0'. I'm unsure which is correct. The image above is a <a href="http://www.network54.com/Forum/78440/thread/1133550200/Sold+the+black+Orient+ana-digi+a+while+back.+Missed+it%2C+so+I+bought+the+aqua+blue.+PIC">link to this review.</a></p>
<p>On that review thread, someone mentions that Citizen now has something similar, the Citizen Wingman VI. Now, I have a Citizen flight watch, the Navihawk Blue Angels:</p>
<p><img src="http://www.phfactor.net/pics/watches/JN0040-58L.jpg" alt="NBA" /></p>
<p>It's nice, and was the apple of my eye for a couple of years, but it has some annoying limitations - there's no backlight and no lume, you can't read it at night! However, the new Eco-drive version does. After searching for a while, I found two models of it: </p>
<p><a href="http://www.watches88.com/pd_citizen_promaster_wingman.cfm"><img src="http://www.phfactor.net/pics/watches/citizen-1.jpg" alt=""></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.watches88.com//pd_citizen_promaster_military_air_jq814051m.cfm"><img src="http://www.phfactor.net/pics/watches/citizen-2.jpg" alt=""></a></p>
<p>(Images are links to the reseller I found, about 300USD each) Not bad. It has a backlight now, though the hands are a bit thin and the face is still harder to read than I'd like. Still and all, getting better. (See Hari's comment - he likes his quite a lot) Then there's the Omega X-33:</p>
<p><img src="http://www.phfactor.net/pics/watches/x-33-gen1.jpg" alt="X33" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.omegawatches.com/index.php?id=297"><img src="http://www.phfactor.net/pics/watches/omegax33.jpg" alt=""></a></p>
<p>(<a href="http://www.timezone.com/library/comarticles/comarticles631681530107424115">TimeZone review here.</a>) Solves all the problems, has multiple timers (very nice for things like flight time, time per tank, leg time, etc) and an alarm loud enough to be heard while flying. Even has a backlight!Too bad it costs, erp, <strong>2600 USD</strong>. Well, so much for <strong>that</strong> idea.</p>
<h3>Conclusions</h3>
<p>If you've got the cash, get the Omega. The Citizen is well priced, usable and just not quite right. I'd probably lean towards the Orient for close-enough and cheapness.</p>
<p>And I really like the Orient in blue. Very nice aesthetics.</p>
<h3>Page update log</h3>
<pre><code></code></pre>
<ul>
<li><p><strong>Updated</strong> 12/9/05: Orient model number, few cosmetic edits.</p>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Updated</strong> 5/27/07: Good comments from Hari, note also <a href="http://www.phfactor.net/wp/2006/08/30/another-x-33-alternative/">this post</a> and <a href="http://www.phfactor.net/wp/2006/07/16/yes-i-need-help/">this one</a> and <a href="http://www.phfactor.net/wp/2006/05/16/orient-analog-digital-review/">my review of the Orient</a> for followups and alternatives. Oh yeah, <a href="http://www.phfactor.net/wp/2006/05/16/omega-and-analog-digital/">and this page on a different Omega.</a> I <strong>do</strong> seem to have A Thing for analog-digital, eh?</p>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Updated</strong> 10/11/07: <a href="http://www.phfactor.net/wp/2007/10/11/more-on-the-omega-x-33/">More X-33 info and updates</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
  </entry>
<entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Added Google analytics to the site]]></title>
    <link href="http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/12/03/Added-Google-analytics-to-the-site.html"/>
    <updated>2014-07-31T17:26:40+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/12/03/Added-Google-analytics-to-the-site.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've now added <a href="http://www.google.com/analytics/">Google analytics</a> to the site, meaning that the header for the blog now has 2 Google javascript links. If this bothers you, please contact me and/or block contacts to www.google-analytics.com.</p>
<p>I don't think it's a problem - the data is anonymous, and the information is tremendously interesting to me. I'll be posting snapshots here once some accumulate.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
<entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blackberry categories blow chunks.]]></title>
    <link href="http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/11/30/Blackberry-categories-blow-chunks.html"/>
    <updated>2014-07-31T17:28:52+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/11/30/Blackberry-categories-blow-chunks.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the <a href="http://www.phfactor.net/bb/bundled_apps.html">main apps review page</a> I said that the OS4 apps had category support. True, they do. However, after using it for quite I while, I have to say that they blow compared to PalmOS.</p>
<p>Much harder to find/use/create. One of the virtues of the palm was the easy of switching categories, and the blackberry lacks this. They're effectively useless.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
<entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple broadband tuner]]></title>
    <link href="http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/11/30/Apple-broadband-tuner.html"/>
    <updated>2014-08-02T23:29:57+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/11/30/Apple-broadband-tuner.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know this has been posted to every Apple blog on the net, but in case you missed it already: Apple has released a small app that sets the TCP window parameters higher.</p>
<p>Or, in plain English, it makes broadband connections faster.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.apple.com/support/downloads/broadbandtuner10.html">It's free. It's small. You can uninstall it.</a></p>
<p>I've installed it, but need to test and see what the results are. From results like this you can see that TCP windows are critical:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.psc.edu/networking/projects/hpn-ssh/"><img src="http://www.phfactor.net/pics/weblog/bdp-v-ssh-win.jpg" alt="data"></a></p>
<p>(Image borrowed from <a href="http://www.psc.edu/networking/projects/hpn-ssh/">http://www.psc.edu/networking/projects/hpn-ssh/</a>)</p>
<p>Gotta love Apple sometimes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
<entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A complete catalog of all the Seiko divers]]></title>
    <link href="http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/11/29/A-complete-catalog-of-all-the-Seiko-divers.html"/>
    <updated>2014-08-02T23:28:48+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/11/29/A-complete-catalog-of-all-the-Seiko-divers.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://orientalwatchsite.com/forum/viewtopic.php?t=1091">Lots and lots of pictures.</a></p>
<p>Personally, I think the Samurai, marinemaster and (of course) SBDB001 are the nicest looking.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
<entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How a watch works - film from Hamilton in 1949]]></title>
    <link href="http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/11/27/How-a-watch-works-film-from-Hamilton-in-1949.html"/>
    <updated>2014-07-31T17:26:10+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/11/27/How-a-watch-works-film-from-Hamilton-in-1949.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is very cool. Archive.org has public-domain film from the legendary Hamilton company, an introductory film on "How a Watch Works." Black and white, download or streamable.</p>
<p>Very cool.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.archive.org/details/HowaWatc1949">http://www.archive.org/details/HowaWatc1949</a></p>
<p>Also on the same site, another Hamilton film on 'What makes a fine watch fine' -
<a href="http://www.archive.org/details/WhatMake1947">http://www.archive.org/details/WhatMake1947</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
<entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Test post for email notification]]></title>
    <link href="http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/11/25/Test-post-for-email-notification.html"/>
    <updated>2014-07-31T17:22:49+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/11/25/Test-post-for-email-notification.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hmm, missed the oh-so-subtle 'notify subscribers' dropdown it added. Hmm.</p>
<p>UPDATE: Notify is now the default. Cool.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
<entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I really want a silent PC so I can run OpenBSD and pf again]]></title>
    <link href="http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/11/25/I-really-want-a-silent-PC-so-I-can-run-OpenBSD-and-pf-again.html"/>
    <updated>2014-07-31T17:23:05+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/11/25/I-really-want-a-silent-PC-so-I-can-run-OpenBSD-and-pf-again.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://205.147.44.194/catalog/product_info.php?products_id=153&amp;osCsid=b44eeb2a32cebf459d424a8c7418bcc1">Preferably one of these</a>. $400, silent, 1U, with Compact Flash for hard drives. It'd make a killer box for OpenBSD. I really miss having pf and level-2 firewalling in place.</p>
<p>Nice for VoIP, too, since <a href="http://slacker.com/~nugget/asterisk4.php">you can use pf/altq</a> to prioritize your VoIP traffic as well. Cool.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
<entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SRV records for Asterisk]]></title>
    <link href="http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/11/25/SRV-records-for-Asterisk.html"/>
    <updated>2014-07-31T17:26:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/11/25/SRV-records-for-Asterisk.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just added SIP and IAX2 records for phfactor.net to UltraDNS, so in <em>theory</em> you can SIP-dial pfh at phfactor.net and it'll work... </p>
<p>Got the idea from <a href="http://slacker.com/~nugget/asterisk2.php">slacker</a>, and found the details on <a href="http://www.voip-info.org/wiki-DNS+SRV">the wonderful VoIP wiki.</a></p>
<p>Looks like we'll convert over to Broadvoice VoIP for all phone - been using their BYOB $6/month plan and a cheap Grandstream 102 with good results. Noticed that Wired Test top-rated them (Broadvoice, that is) and am now shopping for a good Wi-Fi VoIP phone, suggestions welcome!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
<entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Email subscriptions now possible.]]></title>
    <link href="http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/11/23/Email-subscriptions-now-possible.html"/>
    <updated>2014-07-31T17:25:51+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/11/23/Email-subscriptions-now-possible.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve added the <a href="http://watershedstudio.com/portfolio/software/wp-email-notification.html">wordpress email plugin</a> (on the sidebar), so you can sign up for an email every time a post is added. If you’re not using RSS yet, then this might be very useful. Enjoy!</p>
<p><strong>UPDATE:</strong> It's still broken.</p>
<p><strong>UPDATE:</strong> Fixed! Try it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
<entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Opera Mini update]]></title>
    <link href="http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/11/15/Opera-Mini-update.html"/>
    <updated>2014-08-02T23:28:24+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://fnord.phfactor.net/2005/11/15/Opera-Mini-update.html</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So the full error I get is </p>
<pre><code>907 Invalid JAR
HTTP Error 406: Not acceptable.
</code></pre>
<p>Odd. The http://mini.opera.com/mnt tester is OK, so this may be an OS4 issue.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>

  
</feed>
